<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An Encomium on the reverend and valiant Mr. George Walker</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1689</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A39392</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E723</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36229</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15619692</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15619692</idno>
            <idno type="VID">104200</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A39392)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 104200)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1591:68)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An Encomium on the reverend and valiant Mr. George Walker</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for J. Green ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1689.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>"Licensed, September 6. 1689. J. Frasier."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Walker, George, 1645?-1690 --  Poetry.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:104200:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN ENCOMIUM On the REVEREND and VALIANT Mr. George Walker.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>10. Sept: 1689:</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <lg>
               <l>THOU glorious Guide in Honour's rougheſt wayes,</l>
               <l>Whoſe vaſt Deſerts exceeds our greateſt Praiſe;</l>
               <l>Whilſt clamorous throngs of the admiring Croud,</l>
               <l>Their Joy, and thy Deſerts proclaim aloud;</l>
               <l>Whilſt ſucking Babes are taught to liſp thy Name,</l>
               <l>Permit I Eccho the loud Voice of Fame;</l>
               <l>Whoſe Golden Wings ſhall bear thy Name on high,</l>
               <l>And mounting Plumes ſhall beat the diſtant Skye.</l>
               <l>The Conſtant, Valiant, Loyal <hi>Walker</hi>'s Name,</l>
               <l>His Countrey's glory, but the Rebels ſhame:</l>
               <l>The glorious Trophies of his Loyal Sword,</l>
               <l>Immortal Annals ever ſhall record;</l>
               <l>Succeſſive times ſhall long with wonder hear,</l>
               <l>Love and admire, and hold his memory dear:</l>
               <l>Propoſe his Pattern as the utmoſt bound</l>
               <l>Virtue can reach, or may in Man be found:</l>
               <l>The <hi>Roman</hi> Valour muſt by his decline,</l>
               <l>Which like the Sun does leſſer Starrs outſhine.</l>
               <l>Virtue in him exalted does appear,</l>
               <l>Secure by being Good, free both from Guilt and Fear;</l>
               <l>Who bravely for his dear Religion ſtood,</l>
               <l>The Kingdoms glory, and the Nations good:</l>
               <l>The Gown-mens Mirrour when he ſpeaks the Word,</l>
               <l>The Soldiers Pattern when he takes the Sword.</l>
               <l>When Popiſh Legions cloſe Beſieg'd the Town,</l>
               <l>And proudly bragg'd, Their Lives and all's our own;</l>
               <l>The thoughts but on his Dangers chills my Blood,</l>
               <l>I ſhake to think how he undaunted ſtood;</l>
               <l>And Deaths grim Terrors at his awful ſight,</l>
               <l>Grown fearful to his numerous Foes, took flight;</l>
               <l>Like as a Fire ſuppreſt in hollow Cave,</l>
               <l>Diſdains its Priſon, and doth murmuring rave;</l>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:104200:2"/>
               <l>At laſt breaks forth, mounts to its native ſeat,</l>
               <l>Devouring all with flames and rapid heat:</l>
               <l>So mighty <hi>Walker</hi> ſally'd on his Foes;</l>
               <l>Still crown'd with Victory whenſoe're he goes;</l>
               <l>With few and weak, whole Legions put to flight,</l>
               <l>Honour by greateſt Dangers ſhows moſt bright.</l>
               <l>His noble Mind exil'd all ſordid Fear,</l>
               <l>A Soul ſo great and brave could not deſpair.</l>
               <l>As when a troop of thrifty Swains cut down</l>
               <l>With Sythes Earth's ripn'd Riches from the ground,</l>
               <l>Whole ſheaves of Corn lye ſtrew'd upon the Plain,</l>
               <l>So by his Arms were <hi>Iriſh</hi> Rebels ſlain;</l>
               <l>Yet than all theſe an Enemy more fell,</l>
               <l>Within the City Walls did Famine dwell:</l>
               <lg>
                  <l>Famine that never ſhuns the worſt of Meat,</l>
                  <l>Famine that never did a Parlee beat,</l>
                  <l>Famine that never ſounded a retreat;</l>
               </lg>
               <l>Famine, by which their Brave and Valiant dy'd,</l>
               <l>This they encountred, and its power defy'd.</l>
               <l>He when the ghaſtly Emperour of Graves</l>
               <l>(Which braveſt Men of all their force bereaves)</l>
               <l>Star'd in his Face, loud threatning all to kill,</l>
               <l>No fear of Death could force him to do ill:</l>
               <l>He knew the Quarrel happy was, and good,</l>
               <l>For Countreys Cauſe to ſpend his deareſt Blood.</l>
               <l>Like <hi>Staremberg</hi> that bravely did ſupport</l>
               <l>By his great Fortiude the Imperial Court;</l>
               <l>So Reverend <hi>Walker</hi> for three Nations good,</l>
               <l>'Gainſt Number, Sickneſs, Death and Famine ſtood;</l>
               <l>No Dangers or Rewards could make him yield,</l>
               <l>Faithful i'th' Town, and Valiant in the Field:</l>
               <l>Fame, Queen of Immortality, ſhall give</l>
               <l>Him <hi>Balm</hi> when dead, and <hi>Honour</hi> whilſt alive.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>May from his Lips, Juſt, Loyal Sermons flow,</l>
               <l>Whilſt lawrel'd Miters court his Reverend Brown.</l>
               <l>Danger hath Honour, great Deſigns their Fame,</l>
               <l>And Reſolution's Honours faireſt aim.</l>
               <l>Let all brave Souls ſo venture for the Prize,</l>
               <l>They make their Fortune that are <hi>Stout</hi> and <hi>Wiſe.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <p>LICENSED,</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>September 6. 1689.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>J. Fraſier.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>J. Green,</hi> near <hi>Temple-Barr.</hi> 1689.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
